Ihor Pavlenko

Ihor ■Pavlenko ■ 11/10/1987 ■ Skype - linkinrain ■ Ukraine, Kyiv Mayakovs'koho Ave, 7/169, 02225 +380930678937 ■ ihor@pavlenko.ninja

PROFILE

I'm a passionate and open minded JavaScript Front-end developer, with 3+ years of experience in solving complex tasks building Single Page Applications. During my career, I was involved in all aspects of the software development process from early stages of requirements analysis to supporting and refactoring legacy code and mentoring junior developers.

I have a strong knowledge of JavaScript and other related web technologies e.g. HTML/XHTML, DOM, and CSS. I've got a solid understanding and experience with OOD/OOP and design patterns. My experience lies in the scope of modern MVC and front-end frameworks. I am actively practicing and maintaining SCRUM methodology at my projects.

My philosophy towards work are:

- ✓ Clean and maintainable code for the colleagues.
- ✓ Friendly experience for the users.
- ✓ Revenue for business.

WORK EXPERIENCE

GlobalLogic Kyiv Ukraine

GlobalLogic Front-end developer / JavaScript web developer 08/2014 - present

As a member of distributed front-end Scrum team, I was enhancing and maintaining complex content management Single Page Application based on ExtJS + React. This media platform allows users such as composers, audio and video editors, newsmakers, etc. to access, share, play edit, and interacts with multimedia. Besides of that, it provides back-end and front-end API and SDK for the integration with third-party products. The interface has unified theme and components to provide the same look and feel for all integrated components.

Achievements:

- Implemented the lazy loading and lazy rendering search widget;
- Introduced the code quality tools;
- Implemented HTML5 drag and drop API for cross pane interaction in application;
- Implemented APIs for third-party multimedia products using hypermedia REST;
- Introduced CI processes for some modules;

WORK EXPERIENCE

GlobalLogic Front-end developer / Junior JavaScript web Kyiv developer

Ukraine

01/2013 - 08/2014

As a member of distributed front-end Scrum team, I was enhancing and maintaining the complex user management system based on ExtJS + Knockout.js framework.

User management system provides administrators access to a wide range of user management operations such as configuring access levels, license and roles levels. Batch user manipulation such as backup, restore, versioning and migrate user base.

Achievements:

- Improved customer satisfaction by implementing various customerspecific customizations and providing client-side APIs;
- Improved keyboard accessibility for the user's flows;
- Styled the new version of components regarding guidelines;

EDUCATION

B. Sc. Computer National Technical University of Ukraine «Kyiv science Polytechnic Institute»

2012 - 2014

Kyiv Ukraine

B. Sc. National Technical University of Ukraine «Kyiv Engineering Polytechnic Institute»

2004 - 2011

Kyiv Ukraine

SKILLS

Languages & Tools

Frameworks & Libraries

JavaScript (ES5 & ES6)	100%	React	100%
HTML5 / CSS3	80%	Redux	80%
Gulp / Grunt / Webpack	80%	ExtJS	100%
Node.js / npm	60%	Backbone	60%
Jade / Pug	100%	Mocha / Jasmine	80%



Languages

Quality tools and practices

English Professional Ukrainian / Russian Native

TDD	100%
ESLint, JSHint	100%
webdriver.io	60%
weburiver.io	00%
Jest, Karma	100%